Caught between two lines of fire, the Germans gave them two
options: surrender or die. They chose a third.
The Lost Battalion is a history, drama, war film directed by Russell Mulcahy.
Fact-based war drama about an American battalion of over 500 men which gets trapped behind enemy lines
in the Argonne Forest in October 1918 France during the closing weeks of World War I.
Maj. Charles W. Whittlesey, played by Rick Schroder.
Capt. George McMurtry, played by Phil McKee.
Sgt. Gaedeke, played by Jamie Harris.
Lt. Leak, played by Jay Rodan.
Capt. Nelson Holderman, played by Adam James.
Pvt. Phillip Cepeglia, played by Daniel Caltagirone.
The Lost Battalion is a 2001 American war drama television film about the US 77th Division's Lost Battalion during World War I,
which was cut off and surrounded by German forces in the Argonne Forest during the Meuse–Argonne Offensive of 1918.
The film was directed by Russell Mulcahy, written by James Carabatsos,
and stars Rick Schroder as Major Charles Whittlesey.
The film was shot in Luxembourg.
It is an A&E Original Movie, premiering on the network on December 2, 2001.
It is also played on A&E's sister networks such as The History Channel.
It was released on home video in January 2002.
The film explores themes of army, world war i, us
army, based on true story, combat.
The tone is emotional.